https://www.cambridgeshirescouts.org.uk/privacy-policy

Skip to contentPrivacy PolicyHome/Privacy Policy Privacy PolicyJake Stephens2019-08-19T06:09:56+00:00Data Privacy PolicyThis Data Privacy Policy describes the categories of personal data Cambridgeshire County Scout Council process and for what purposes. Cambridgeshire County Scout Council are committed to collecting and using such data fairly and in accordance with the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR), the regulations set by the European Union, and Data Protection Act 2018 (DPA 2018), the UK law that encompasses the GDPR.This Privacy Policy applies to members, parents/guardians of youth members, volunteers, employees, contractors, suppliers, supporters, donors and members of the public who will make contact with Cambridgeshire County Scout CouncilWho we areCambridgeshire County Scout Council are a registered charity with the Charity Commission for England & Wales; charity number 300725. The Data Controller for Cambridgeshire County Scout Council is the Executive Committee who are appointed at an Annual General Meeting and are Charity Trustees.From this point on Cambridgeshire County Scout Council also known as Cambridgeshire County Scouts or Cambridgeshire Scouts may be referred to as “we”. Being a small charity, we are not required to appoint a Data Protection Officer.The data we may process· The majority of the personal information we hold, is provided to us directly by you or by the parents or legal guardians of youth members verbally or in paper form, digital form or via our online membership system Compass. In the case of adult members and volunteers, data may also be provided by third parties, such as the England & Wales – Disclosure and Barring Service (DBS),Where a member is under the age of 18, this information will only be obtained from a parent or guardian and cannot be provided by the young person.We may collect the following personal information:· Personal contact details such as name, title, address, telephone numbers and personal email address – so that we can contact you.· Date of birth – so that we can ensure young people are allocated to the appropriate Section for their age and that adults are old enough to take on an appointment with Scouting.· Gender – so that we can address individuals correctly and accommodate for any specific needs.· Emergency contact information – so that we are able to contact someone in the event of an emergency.· Government identification numbers e.g. national insurance, driving licence, passport – to be able to process volunteer criminal record checks.· Bank account details, payroll information and tax status information – so that we are able to pay any staff that might be employed by us and collect gift aid from HMRC where donations are made.8· training records – so that members can track their progression through the Scout programme or adult training scheme.· Race or ethnic origin – so that we can make suitable arrangements based on members cultural needs.· Health records – so that we can make suitable arrangements based on members medical needs.· Criminal records checks – to ensure Scouting is a safe space for young people and adults.The lawful basis we process your data byWe comply with our obligations under the GDPR and DPA 2018 by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.In most cases the lawful basis for processing will be through the performance of a contract for personal data and as legitimate interests for your sensitive data.We use personal data for the following purposes:· to provide information about Scout meetings, activities, training courses and events to our members and other volunteers in Cambridgeshire Scout County· to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public in a geographic area as specified in our constitution· to administer membership records· to fundraise and promote the interests of Scouting· to manage our volunteers· to maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications)· to inform you of news, events, activities and services being run or attended by Cambridgeshire Scout County· to ensure and evidence your suitability if volunteering for a role in Scouting· to contact your next of kin in the event of an emergency· to ensure you have and maintain the correct qualifications and skills.We use personal sensitive data for the following purposes:· for the protection of a person’s health and safety whilst in the care of Cambridgeshire Scout County· to respect a person’s religious beliefs with regards to activities, food and holidays· for equal opportunity monitoring and reporting.Our retention periodsWe will keep certain types of information for different periods of time in line with our retention policy.The Scout Association’s Data Protection Policy can be found here and the Data Privacy Notice here.Sharing your informationYoung people and other data subjectsWe will normally only share personal information with adult volunteers holding an appointment in the Cambridgeshire Scout CountyAdult volunteersWe will normally only share personal information with adult volunteers holding appropriate appointments within the line management structure of The Scout Association for the [Cambridgeshire Scout County as well as with The Scout Association Headquarters as joint data controllers.All data subjectsWe will however share your personal information with others outside of [Cambridgeshire Scout County where we need meet a legal obligation. This may include The Scout Association and its insurance subsidiary (Unity Insurance Services), local authority services and law enforcement. We will only share your personal information to the extent needed for those purposes.We will only share your data with third parties outside of the organisation where there is a legitimate reason to do so.How we store your personal dataWe generally store personal information in the following ways:Compass – is the online membership system of The Scout Association, this system is used for the collection and storage of adult volunteer personal data.MailChimp – is used to distribute emails to mailing lists extracted from Compass.Scouts EMS – is used for some of our major events to collect personal data needed to run the event safely and efficiently.Website – Is a server dedicated to Cambridgeshire Scouts and we may store names & email addresses for booking and login purposes.Other Third Parties – we may sometimes contract with other third parties to supply services to you on our behalf and they may collect and store your data. We may also use a third party to provide a data redaction service. Where any of your data is required for such a purpose, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data will be handled safely, securely and in accordance with your rights, our obligations and the obligation of the third party with respect to GDPR.In addition, adult volunteers may hold some personal data on local spreadsheets/databases.Paper documents are sometimes used to capture and retain some data for example:· Gift Aid administration· Event registration· Health and contact records forms (for events)· Events coordination with event organisersPaper records for events may also be used rather than relying on secure digital systems, as events may be held where internet and digital access will not be available. We will minimise the use of paper to only what is required for the event and ensured its secure disposal within a reasonable time after the event has ended.Further processingIf we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processingHow we provide this privacy noticeA link to this website page is included in cambridgeshirescouts.org.uk email footer. A printed version is also available on request.Your rightsAs a Data Subject, you have the right to object to how we process your personal information. You also have the right to access, correct, sometimes delete and restrict the personal information we use. In addition, you have a right to complain to us and to the Information Commissioner’s Office (www.ico.org.uk).Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR and DPA 2018, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:· The right to be informed – you have a right to know how your data will be used by us.· The right to access your personal data – you can ask us to share with you the data we have about you. This is a Data Subject Access Request.· The right to rectification – this just means you can update your data if it’s inaccurate or if something is missing. Adult members will be able to edit and update some information directly on The Scout Association’s Compass membership system.· The right to erasure – this means that you have the right to request that we delete any personal data we have about you. There are some exceptions, for example, some information will be held by The Scout Association for legal reasons.· The right to restrict processing – if you think that we are not processing your data in line with this privacy notice then you have the right to restrict any further use of that data until the issue is resolved.· The right to data portability – this means that if you ask us we will have to share your data with you in a way that can be read digitally – such as a pdf. This makes it easier to share information with others.· The right to object – you can object to the ways your data is being used.· Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling – this protects you in cases where decision are being made about you based entirely on automated processes rather than a human input, it’s highly unlikely that this will be used by us.Website CookiesForms Related CookiesWhen you submit data through a form such as those found on our contact pages or comment forms, cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.Third Party CookiesIn some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official Google Privacy information page.Social Media CookiesWe also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways.For these to work the following social media sites including; Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and YouTube, will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.Who to contactIf you have any queries relating to this Privacy Notice or our use of your personal data, please contact us by email to countyoffice@cambridgeshirescouts.org.ukVersion number and date of the last review[Version 03 – 01/07/2019
We use cookies to ensure you get the best experience on our website. Privacy PolicyAccept
